Guide to the Constance Buell Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Constance Buell Papers
1918-1976
RG 140
Yale University Divinity School Library
2
(4 boxes)
Substantive letters and detailed diary entries document Buell's daily work as a missionary, her relationships with colleagues, and her views on events in China. Constance Buell was an educational missionary in north China from 1919 to 1951, serving under the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions. She taught at Kobe College in Japan from 1952 to 1958.
Buell, Constance, 1891-1987
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Constance Buell.
Biographical / Historical
1891 Dec 15 Born in Wellesley Hills, MA
1913 Graduated from Wellesley College, began teaching in Massachusetts schools
1919-1951 Served under North China Mission of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions; Principal of Stanley Memorial School for girls; Vice-principal under a Chinese principal after the school became coeducational. In addition to her administrative responsibilities, she also taught English and music. Spent time in a Japanese internment camp at Weihsien.
1943 Repatriated on the Gripsholm
1946 Returned to China
1952-1958 Taught English at Kobe College, Japan until her retirement
1987 Died
Scope and Contents
This is a compact but valuable collection that provides thorough documentation of Constance Buell's education work in Tientsin [now Tianjian], China. These papers complement the papers of Buell's American Board colleague in Tientsin, Earle Ballou (YDSL RG165). Substantive letters to family and friends and fairly consistent and detailed diary entries provide insight into Buell's daily work, relationships with colleagues, and views on events in China. Buell's internment in Weihsien is not well documented. There are more than 150 photographs; most are well identified. Buell is a prime example of an intelligent and well-educated single woman who carved out for herself a missionary career that provided professional challenge, ample opportunity for travel and adventure, and satisfying relationships with colleagues.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1919-1976, n.d.
II. Diaries, 1918-1958
III. Writings and Notes, 1938-1958, n.d.
IV. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1920-1951
V. Photographs, 1952-1958, n.d.
Missions -- China; Women missionaries; Missionaries; Buell, Constance, 1891-1987; American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions
- Correspondence, 1919-1976, n.d.; Series I
  - Family correspondence, 1919-1929 (Box 1, Folder 1-16)
  - Family correspondence, 1930-1938, 1941-1955 (Box 2, Folder 17-24)
  - Letters from CB to colleagues and supporters, 1931-1963, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 25-29)
  - Letters from Carolyn Sewall to CB and CB's family, 1919-1946, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Letters from other Western colleagues and supporters, 1919-1979 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letters from former students and Asian colleagues, including from Chinese friends in China following Communist takeover and from Tomo Takami, with enclosed biographical sketch, 1939-1976, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
- Diaries, 1918-1958; Series II
  - Diaries of CB, 1918-1958 (Box 3, Folder 34-35)
- Writings and Notes, 1938-1958, n.d.; Series III
  - By CB, 1938-1958, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 36-37)
  - By Kobe College students, 1956-1957, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1938-1958, n.d.; Series IV
  - Biographical material re. CB, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Financial records, 1931, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Scrapbook re. Kang Wei Lu Church Choir, 1933-1948 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Programmes of the Stanley Club, Tientsin, 1920-1935 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Collected material re. Kobe College, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous collected material, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Photographs, 1952-1958, n.d.; Series V
  - China: photographs of CB, Western colleagues (including Arthur Smith and Chauncey Goodrich), Chinese students and colleagues, scenes, buildings (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Japan: photographs of Kobe College and students, ca. 1952-1958 (Box 4, Folder 46)